hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermitcraft now
today i have a proposal that will bring
about the end of the hermitcraft civil
war but i'm not going to tell you what
it is right now because i have invited
absolutely everybody involved in the
civil war to meet me later where i can
explain how this whole thing is going to
work out so we'll find out about that
later on for now i've been working on
making my little chest system a little
bit prettier because as it stands it's
not much to look at and i definitely
have realized i don't have enough chests
for all of my various different items
but for the time being i think this
should keep me busy to be honest with
you i have spent this entire season
without any proper item system and you
know what it's really not bothered me
that much apart from the wasted hours
trying to find something down here
nothing really has gone wrong but look
at this this is an absolute mess so i
talked about this very important box
right here and it's full of puffer fish
now that's because i want to work on a
trap in the g-team base that involves it
and hey if you watched my last episode
you probably already know what this is
so let's head on over there shall we as
you can see i've got this bubble
elevator and
you may have seen my trap video
that i just put out and one of those is
a puffer fish trap and that's what i'm
going to load in here so when they get
in this base not only will they have
multiple surprises from all of the traps
but
they're going to have even the transport
system which we will internally know not
to use so they'll go in here that's
where we've got the redstone input but
it's going to be so quick so all i'm
going to do
is completely empty this area out so i
can make the redstone that i need to
i've just cleared all of this out and
docker said green do you have a minute
yes i guess
i guess i this better not be a trap this
better not be a trap
come join us on discord i feel like i'm
walking into a trap right now they're at
the peace flag i said no pvp okay okay
they've agreed
i have a deal all right let's uh let's
go and find out oh i can see i can see
green
oh
hello green where are you
down here in the hole we had a little
invest you know investigation going on
and i have a little deal dude
okay we have a player in our team
we don't want him anymore
mambo come on come on you don't want red
no no no no no no no no no no no
apparently it's me i can't believe this
why why wouldn't you want mumbo on your
team
dude
you know exactly what's going on man i
know it
is it the bananas
bananas
come on man
no no no no
you can have him but not for free i have
one demand because technically he's a
he's you know one of our team members
right
okay so
you you've uh you've been rumbled mum
but i'm not really surprised to be
honest with you um i don't even know
where to stand
not over here
so right okay we'll we'll have him back
what do you want
yeah you can have him yeah but only
without his mustachio
oh no
you would have to go that's the source
of his power
well you're keeping it
yep for the time as long as the war
keeps on going no mustachio for any war
included activities by
i don't i can't use the machine like
that
no
no no surely not you're not you're not
you're not considering this are you we
could really use the manpower come on uh
there's got to be another way diamonds
you want diamonds
no no
good mumbo you're going to have to take
one for the team buddy
so i have to lose the music can i keep
the sunglasses
i think yeah you can keep the sunglasses
you got a deal
yeah we got a deal
fair enough all right we got a deal fair
enough
whether mumbo likes it or not we need
him no i know i don't think i've got a
choice in the matter to be honest with
you yeah so so i'm now officially a gt
member not yet we need to go over to the
machine
oh yeah i want to see this
okay here we are
the machine have you have you seen this
machine dark and ren
no man
nope i'm i'm intrigued by it i heard
it's the most crazy redstone device we
have on here it's it's one of the
derpiest things i've ever seen it's like
80 magic it's been a while since you've
used it actually i i guess yeah it's
been actually it's been a long time
since this has been used we didn't we
don't actually don't get many customers
mainly because last time it was used
jevon gave us so many diamonds we've not
needed to use it ever yeah exactly we've
cashed out
uh all right doc i guess you can uh do
the honors
just hit the ground button in the middle
and it will remove his mustache
i'm kind of scared all right here we go
here we go for the third time
[Music]
i forgot about this
this is the best
[Applause]
i hope it still works
[Laughter]
r.i.p mustache well that should have
worked
oh my god i've never seen it in real
life it is glorious
well you should have seen green with a
moustache that was one of the worst
things ever i mean yeah it didn't it
didn't look good on me
where's it gone oh yeah i forgot to tell
you guys it we don't know where it goes
the machine just relocates it somewhere
on the server so good luck finding it
and then mumbo doesn't get it back until
it's removed and then pasted back on his
face
yeah we've even got a machine i think
you made a machine right it just goes
like yeah yeah just shoots it straight
on
yeah it's a little bit painful but it's
quite an industrial unit but it yeah it
does the trick
so that's pretty much it now mumbo is
now no longer a mole to be fair i don't
think you were much of a mole to begin
with no i mean
not really i
i must admit it wasn't the best job role
for me um
i don't think i did a single mole task
potentially correctly and now that i've
been fired i can safely say that i was
trying to you know sugarcoat everything
you were not even able to press a button
twice come on
don't even talk about that
well uh
welcome to the g team i guess
it's nice to be here
i know i know i know rendog's just
joined team star okay
you might have another mole in your
mitts because
have you noticed what's at the end of
his name
dog
dog have you have you not noticed e dog
the dog
dog g he's got a g at the end of his
name
oh my god oh
well let's just hop straight back into
this so the machine that i'm going to be
making is a puffer fish dispenser the
problem with this is that i cannot test
it without dying
so
the idea is that we fill up these
dispensers with pufferfish now i'm going
to be conservative and not put lots in
when you go inside it's going to
activate this piston which is going to
block off the top
if you've seen my trap video you know
how this works and it's actually one of
my favorite ones that came out of that
video and it's very very simple so these
all have dispensers in them
and these have pufferfish inside
when they walk over this pressure plate
here it's going to send a signal
it's going to pull away these pistons
revealing the dispensers they're going
to pump out the puffer fish and then the
top will seal off and they'll be trapped
in there with puffer fish and to be
honest with you there's not a lot they
can do because they
will get them very very quickly and now
i just need to remember how to redstone
because this is the easy bit
the hard bit is actually wiring it up i
don't know the best way to power
everything
you know watching me do redstone must be
a lot like watching like a swimmer do
ballet or something else that they just
totally don't know what they're talking
about they're an expert in one thing
but they really shouldn't talk about
ballet i'm not sure that's the right
that's the right analogy but you get
what i mean i have no idea what i'm
doing here
while i was making this trap it was
actually time to go and do that
explanation about the end of the civil
war that i mentioned right at the start
of the video so we're gonna go skip to
that really quick and then come back to
this a little bit later
sorry that it's a little bit confusing
in today's episode welcome everybody i
have gathered everyone here because this
war
doesn't seem to have an end in sight
and i'm here to propose a way
to finish it if everybody is interested
yeah let's do it
hear me out first before you try to hear
me out first
well actually there's a bit of side
information um it turns out guys that
mumbo was a mole and um he's now back on
our team
you knew it i am shocked you may notice
that
he's missing a vital piece of equipment
and that's part of his punishment for
being a mole
it didn't come for free though guys look
at our base oh
oh my god
[Laughter]
nice a bit of mumbo is still on the star
team i like it
anyway the reason that i've got everyone
here is because i am going to propose a
way to finish this war and i propose and
here it is
[Music]
i found a note inside my uniform that
you gave me gee i mean i could have used
that whatever anyway
anyway anyway anyway i propose a capture
the flag i've asked your team to produce
three flags for you that represent you
have you got those yeah they are
brilliant bring out the flavor i've also
already worked i've also got our flags
right here
now the oh sorry sorry mambo
[Laughter]
okay so each team
has three flags and we're going to play
this out as a big capture the flag game
that lasts over a few days you'll see on
the back wall there a bunch of heads
there are 15 on each side team star and
the g team
and each one of these heads represents a
life
now if you die while trying to get one
of the flags you have to remove a head
and then that's as many lives you got so
if you hit zero lives you lose the war
and the other win condition is if you
retrieve all three of the opposition's
flags you win
so there's two ways of doing this you
can either go all out pvp or you can try
and get the flags but the primary goal
are the flags okay is everyone on board
okay
so there's a few rules that we're going
to introduce now to make sure that it's
kind of an even playing field we're
going to not use any elytra during this
fight and we're going to only use iron
armor just so it's nice and fair ish
and keep it nice and fun now if you do
happen to break any of these rules i
don't really i don't really care like
it's not it's not it's not a big deal
it's really not a big deal however let's
try and keep it nice and fun and
hopefully
we'll get all of i mean guys go and grab
their flag right there go and grab the
flags i was thinking about doing that
all right let's go everyone can go and
hide their flags in their base and from
this point on
you are free to go and grab each other's
flags
is everyone cool everyone good on the
rules
sounds good
sweet yeah sure so after that meeting we
now know the rules of engagement but to
be honest with you the rules don't
really matter too much it's just a game
for fun like we're not actually worried
if someone uses their elytra that only
means by the way just so i can clarify
if you use your elytra outside of the
war that's absolutely fine it's only
like if you're going on the attack for
example it would be pretty ungentlemanly
of me if i flew over flew to the top of
their base knocked out those tnt cannons
and called that fair game you know so
basically it's just electro if you're
just gonna fly there it's probably
better to walk like i said it really
doesn't matter anyway i have finally
finished
this pufferfish dispensing machine this
should catch anybody using this fairly
easily so it's not actually got any puff
fish at the moment so i can show you how
it looks so obviously this is all
completely hidden and they should in
theory just walk in it dispenses and you
see all those items they will be
pufferfish now what i've done is i've
actually put in some staircases here and
water logged and because that's a source
block on the left here what it should do
is when this dispenses puffer fish it
will also dispense a block of water
leaving all of these blocks in here in
this column here completely source
blocks so they should get pushed all the
way to the top along with the puffer
fish and there's really not a lot they
can do
however
i
probably need to test this
but i'm not sure i really want to let's
get all these puffer fish in there
proper place and i guess we'll just hope
it works no i've i've got to test this
haven't i there's no other way to do
this i've got to test it but pufferfish
are a very very expensive piece of
equipment all right so let's reset this
shouldn't dispense anything you know my
redstone might look like it belongs in
2012 but it works like it's very it's
very very like held together by duct
tape and string
but it definitely works every single
part of it works flawlessly so i got
this t flip-flop right and it actually
pushes the redstone away from these two
bits the dispensers and the pistons but
then it pushes it into
the bit at the top which seals off the
the top of it meaning that they can't
escape genius i tell you genius i could
get into redstone i think right
let's test this but let's actually get
rid of all of our stuff
puffer fish here i come
and yep okay
there's really there there's really not
there's not a lot you can do
yeah there's really not a lot you can oh
i'm back in my base
well we know that it works oh no
i got rid of my ender chest
why
why did i do that
oh
no
okay well actually the trip in the
nether's not so bad we have successfully
made one trap so basically with this
whole new capture the flag thing i want
to place all three of our flags well
defended and i want to put some traps in
the general area of the base
so hopefully we can get a good chunk of
their lives when they come to get our
flags now where is a good portal to get
out of here i can't believe this is how
i need to get to the base right now
i'm on the wrong side of thin
this has been the worst test ever
i'm almost there
what a horrible journey are all those oh
the pufferfish despawn oh no the
pufferfish is still there
okay let's load this back up we now know
that it completely works
and hopefully we can get our other
puffer fish back in their buckets
because puffer fish are expensive and
they are a brilliant way to get someone
with a trap
ah um
yeah i didn't think this through did i
come here little puffer fish
one more come on little fella
no come on
there we go all the puffer fish are back
in their buckets brilliant so nothing
has been wasted
i think the only thing to do now
is to replace one block of water
and place that block back there and it
should reset let's hope it doesn't
dispense anything oh you know what
it might be it might be pretty terrible
redstone in there but it does it matter
if it's terrible if it works flawlessly
like seriously it it works one way it
doesn't dispense them on the way out you
can reset it easily
i've put two
puffer fish i've put two puffer fish in
each one so if for some reason someone
goes in it twice it'll get them again
absolutely brilliant and we've got
pufferfish to spare as well i am really
happy with this guys are you are you
proud of me please if you're proud of me
and my redstoning let me know because
this took a really long time
this is way better than the one that i
made in my trap video by the way way way
better so
that is it put that block there it
should bubble elevator all the way to
the top
and that should be a secure kill as long
as they use it that's the main thing
they've got to use it but i'm afraid
that's all i've got time for today but a
lot has happened we did a little bit of
work in the base not a lot but we'll get
back to that after the war we also have
made that trap behind me the puffer fish
one we also got our main mumbo man back
mumbo gumbo
slightly underpowered because
the source of his power has been removed
his mustache and it ended up it ended up
on the team star base which is
absolutely fantastic so we know where to
get it back at the end of all of this
there it is over there
it actually looks like a pair of eyes
there it is right there you can see it's
got a couple of eyes just above the
mustache it's absolutely perfect yeah i
don't want to go too close there
and we also set out the rules for the
new capture the flag finale of this war
which i'm super excited about now
because this will see a definite winner
at the end
and it will be absolutely brilliant
honestly i don't mind who wins i'm just
i'm just thankful that we got to do this
at all because this has been really
really fun so that's it for me everyone
i hope you've enjoyed this video and
please let me know in the comments as
well if you're excited for the capture
the flag game
good bye